<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mocha Dick</title>
    <link>http://ehabit.github.io/mochadick/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Mocha Dick</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2015 08:46:41 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://ehabit.github.io/mochadick/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The World is a Dangerous Place</title>
      <link>http://ehabit.github.io/mochadick/post/spec/world/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2015 08:46:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ehabit.github.io/mochadick/post/spec/world/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-fog:1b10292b89f0ac4ad5e24cbfd07e192e&#34;&gt;The Fog&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Land lovers say the fog is a curse from Mocha Dick to protect the oceans from man.  Sea dogs and pirates say it is a test from Davy Jones himself to judge the worthy.  If you want to be a whaler, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to face the fog.  If you are within 30 steps of an ocean or beach you&amp;rsquo;ll find yourself in a slight fog.  If you are on a beach type biome it thickens into a mild fog and out on the ocean biomes you get the thick nasty.  The ocean waters are murky from the fog as well making it difficult to locate sea creatures without some improved technology.   You&amp;rsquo;ve heard of a brave inventor from a nearby province who has crafted a whale oil lamp that pushes back the fog.  If only you had some whale oil&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;ocean-waters:1b10292b89f0ac4ad5e24cbfd07e192e&#34;&gt;Ocean Waters&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The waters of the oceans are murky and difficult to explore without the appropriate whale oil light sources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-white-whale-dimension:1b10292b89f0ac4ad5e24cbfd07e192e&#34;&gt;The White Whale Dimension&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The White Whate Dimension is a dark and dangerous place.  Mocha Dick is said to live there.  Players must sail out over an ocean on a trans-dimensionally upgraded boat at sunset and activate a whale bone compass to travel here.  Pirate villagers and slavers can be found and traded with here as well.  The white whale dimension is deep and dark ocean.  It is said a Kraken lurks in the depths, obedient only to Davy Jones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;water-world:1b10292b89f0ac4ad5e24cbfd07e192e&#34;&gt;Water World&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Water World is an entirely aquatic world.  Players must have an end game boat with a submarine upgrade attached.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mocha Dick Items</title>
      <link>http://ehabit.github.io/mochadick/post/spec/items/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2015 16:39:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ehabit.github.io/mochadick/post/spec/items/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Mocha Dick focuses on the great age of sailing, whaling and piracy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;harpoons-and-weapons:14154d75c456ce7e0244b9b9c074dce1&#34;&gt;Harpoons and Weapons&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;stone-harpoon:14154d75c456ce7e0244b9b9c074dce1&#34;&gt;Stone Harpoon&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A basic whale hunting tool used by Inuit whale hunters.  Can damage baby whales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;iron-harpoon:14154d75c456ce7e0244b9b9c074dce1&#34;&gt;Iron Harpoon&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An iron thrown harpoon. More damage than a stone harpoon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;obsidian-tipped-harpoon:14154d75c456ce7e0244b9b9c074dce1&#34;&gt;Obsidian Tipped Harpoon&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A mid-tier harpoon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;whale-bone-harpoon:14154d75c456ce7e0244b9b9c074dce1&#34;&gt;Whale Bone Harpoon&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A mid-tier harpoon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;scrimshaw-musket:14154d75c456ce7e0244b9b9c074dce1&#34;&gt;Scrimshaw Musket&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A basic musket.  Takes a while to reload and isn&amp;rsquo;t very accurate, but packs a punch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;scrimshaw-blunderbuss:14154d75c456ce7e0244b9b9c074dce1&#34;&gt;Scrimshaw Blunderbuss&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A high-tier weapon.  The shells the blunderbuss use take a lot of processing to create in goodly quantities, but most sea dogs find this to be well worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;scrimshaw-revolver:14154d75c456ce7e0244b9b9c074dce1&#34;&gt;Scrimshaw Revolver&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;End game Mocha Dick item can be traded for with Pirate Villagers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;boats:14154d75c456ce7e0244b9b9c074dce1&#34;&gt;Boats&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;whaling-canoe:14154d75c456ce7e0244b9b9c074dce1&#34;&gt;Whaling Canoe&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A basic wooden whaling canoe improves the sturdiness of the boat. This is a basic upgrade from the vanilla Minecraft boats.  Can attach a single whaling upgrade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;whaling-sail-boat:14154d75c456ce7e0244b9b9c074dce1&#34;&gt;Whaling Sail Boat&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A whaling sail boat moves faster than whaling canoes and can have three whaling upgrades attached.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;whaler:14154d75c456ce7e0244b9b9c074dce1&#34;&gt;Whaler&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A mid-tier whaling boat.  Suitable for hunting many of the adult whales in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;steam-powered-whaler:14154d75c456ce7e0244b9b9c074dce1&#34;&gt;Steam Powered Whaler&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An upper tier whaling boat.  Powered by whale oil burning to generate steam.  High hit points but burns whale oil very fast and cannot move without a whale oil supply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;whalebone-pirate-ship:14154d75c456ce7e0244b9b9c074dce1&#34;&gt;Whalebone Pirate Ship&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An upper tier whaling boat.  Not quite as tanky as the steam powered whaler, but doesn&amp;rsquo;t constantly consume whale oil.  Costs Mocha Dick&amp;rsquo;s whale bones to create.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;boat-attachments:14154d75c456ce7e0244b9b9c074dce1&#34;&gt;Boat Attachments&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;whale-oil-lamp:14154d75c456ce7e0244b9b9c074dce1&#34;&gt;Whale Oil Lamp&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A light source for whaling boats to reduce the ocean fog around their vessel and increase visibility on the oceans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;whale-oil-try-pot:14154d75c456ce7e0244b9b9c074dce1&#34;&gt;Whale Oil Try Pot&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A try pot the player can interact with while onboard the vessel.  Try pots are used to boil down whale blubber into whale oil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;whale-oil-furnace:14154d75c456ce7e0244b9b9c074dce1&#34;&gt;Whale Oil Furnace&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A basic furnace the player can use and interact with while onboard the vessel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;harpoon-gun:14154d75c456ce7e0244b9b9c074dce1&#34;&gt;Harpoon Gun&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A necessary whaler&amp;rsquo;s weapon.  It provides increased force and accuracy for harpoons and is necessary to shoot some of the more advanced harpoons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;fishing-net:14154d75c456ce7e0244b9b9c074dce1&#34;&gt;Fishing Net&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gathers fishes for you as you sail.  An excellent and reliable food source on the open sea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;hammock:14154d75c456ce7e0244b9b9c074dce1&#34;&gt;Hammock&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Acts like a sleeping bag from open blocks, allowing players to go to sleep on their boat to change time of day.  This item does not change a player&amp;rsquo;s spawn point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;ice-breaker:14154d75c456ce7e0244b9b9c074dce1&#34;&gt;Ice Breaker&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allows players to sail through frozen ocean biomes. Their boat breaks any ice in front of them to clear a path to sail through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;heat-shield:14154d75c456ce7e0244b9b9c074dce1&#34;&gt;Heat Shield&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allows players to sail through lava.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;captain-s-chest:14154d75c456ce7e0244b9b9c074dce1&#34;&gt;Captain&amp;rsquo;s Chest&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A double chest&amp;rsquo;s worth of ender-chest-like storage that can only be access from a Captain&amp;rsquo;s Chest block item or from on a boat with the appropriate Captain&amp;rsquo;s Chest attachment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;artificials-gills-and-positive-pressure-bubble:14154d75c456ce7e0244b9b9c074dce1&#34;&gt;Artificials Gills and Positive Pressure Bubble&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An end game Mocha Dick boat attachment that allows boats to go underwater.  Boats burn whale oil to provide oxygen to the player.  The submarine upgrade is necessary to hunt the Kraken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;sail-of-endless-winds:14154d75c456ce7e0244b9b9c074dce1&#34;&gt;Sail of Endless Winds&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An end game Mocha Dick boat attachment is only usable on high tier boats.  It grants the boat creative flight so players can sail through the air while in their boats.  This item can only be traded for with pirate villagers in the white whale dimension.  They will only accept White Whale bone scrimshaw for the item.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;blackbeard-s-warp-drive:14154d75c456ce7e0244b9b9c074dce1&#34;&gt;Blackbeard&amp;rsquo;s Warp Drive&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The old bastard enslaved the Einstein of his generation to build this device for him.  Thousands of whales were slain in its construction.  Blackbeard then killed the brilliant inventor to make sure that no others would possess the knowledge to create such a device.  It allows the boat to create a warp field around itself and jump ahead for short periods of time, burning massive amounts of whale oil in the process.  Players can blink anywhere from 10 to 2000 blocks away.  It is unknown where to find or how to build this item.  It is known that this item is required to reach the Water World dimension where Blackbeard supposedly hid his treasure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;blocks:14154d75c456ce7e0244b9b9c074dce1&#34;&gt;Blocks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;woodworker-s-bench:14154d75c456ce7e0244b9b9c074dce1&#34;&gt;Woodworker&amp;rsquo;s Bench&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is used to craft boat components necessary to construct whaling boats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;boatworks:14154d75c456ce7e0244b9b9c074dce1&#34;&gt;Boatworks&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Used to build new whaling boats.  Allows players to attach upgrades to their vessels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;whale-oil-furnace-1:14154d75c456ce7e0244b9b9c074dce1&#34;&gt;Whale Oil Furnace&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A basic furnace powered by whale oil rather than coal.  Provides efficiency boost over regular furnaces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;slaver-s-pit:14154d75c456ce7e0244b9b9c074dce1&#34;&gt;Slaver&amp;rsquo;s Pit&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A multi-block structure that allows whalers to enslave villagers to perform various menial tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;slaver-s-pit-with-lumberjack-attachment:14154d75c456ce7e0244b9b9c074dce1&#34;&gt;Slaver&amp;rsquo;s Pit with Lumberjack attachment&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ruthless whalers don&amp;rsquo;t have time to cut wood.  So, they enslave villagers to cut wood for them.  This is a large multi-block structure that cuts and harvests a nearby wood farm based on how many villagers are trapped within.  Slavers must supply food and water to their slaves in the pit or they will start to die.  Slavers will also need to supply basic stone axes for the slaves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;slaver-s-pit-with-cotton-picker-attachment:14154d75c456ce7e0244b9b9c074dce1&#34;&gt;Slaver&amp;rsquo;s Pit with Cotton Picker attachment&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ruthless whalers don&amp;rsquo;t have time to till and harvest crops.  So, they enslave villagers to do this work for them.  This is a large multi-block structure that plants and harvests a nearby field based on how many villagers are trapped within.  Slavers must supply water and food to their slaves in the pit or they will start to die.  It&amp;rsquo;s easy to make this a self-sustaining structure with a proper ratio of slave to crop.  Slaves within cannot outgrow the amount of food they generate based on the size of the crop around them or they will die unless otherwise supplied with food.  Slavers will also need to supply basic stone hoes for the slaves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;slaver-s-pit-with-gladiator-attachment:14154d75c456ce7e0244b9b9c074dce1&#34;&gt;Slaver&amp;rsquo;s Pit with Gladiator attachment&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a large multi-block structure that kills mobs in a nearby arena.  Powered by villagers enslaved within.  Slaves must be supplied with food, water, and stone swords or better.  There is a slave mortality rate regardless.  Harvests items and experience from mobs killed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-whale-oil-lighthouse:14154d75c456ce7e0244b9b9c074dce1&#34;&gt;A Whale Oil Lighthouse&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dissipates fog in a radius along where it is built, usually on a shoreline.  Very useful for ports and coastal towns.  Consumes whale oil to provide light.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;miscellaneous-items:14154d75c456ce7e0244b9b9c074dce1&#34;&gt;Miscellaneous Items&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;wine-bottle:14154d75c456ce7e0244b9b9c074dce1&#34;&gt;Wine Bottle&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Players can break these on their boats to name them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;shackles:14154d75c456ce7e0244b9b9c074dce1&#34;&gt;Shackles&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allows a player to turn a villager into a slave.  Slaves can&amp;rsquo;t trade, but they can be traded and put into pits to do work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;davy-jones-ring:14154d75c456ce7e0244b9b9c074dce1&#34;&gt;Davy Jones&amp;rsquo; Ring&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Summons a Kraken.  Players must be in the white whale dimension and must be near the ocean floor in an advanced baot with a submarine upgrade.  Davy Jones&amp;rsquo; Ring must be traded for with Pirate villagers in the White Whale dimension.  It costs a large amount of slave chattel to attain this item.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;davy-jones-locker:14154d75c456ce7e0244b9b9c074dce1&#34;&gt;Davy Jones&amp;rsquo; Locker&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What lies within this legendary chest remains a mystery.  It is believed by many whalers that Davy Jones&amp;rsquo; Kraken defends his locker in the depths of the sea.  But even if you find it, how will you open it?  Players must be clever to break into this chest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;whale-drops:14154d75c456ce7e0244b9b9c074dce1&#34;&gt;Whale Drops&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;baby-whale-blubber:14154d75c456ce7e0244b9b9c074dce1&#34;&gt;Baby Whale Blubber&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;baby-whale-bone:14154d75c456ce7e0244b9b9c074dce1&#34;&gt;Baby Whale Bone&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;whale-blubber:14154d75c456ce7e0244b9b9c074dce1&#34;&gt;Whale Blubber&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;whale-bone:14154d75c456ce7e0244b9b9c074dce1&#34;&gt;Whale Bone&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;spermaceti:14154d75c456ce7e0244b9b9c074dce1&#34;&gt;Spermaceti&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;nether-whale-blubber:14154d75c456ce7e0244b9b9c074dce1&#34;&gt;Nether Whale Blubber&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;white-whale-blubber:14154d75c456ce7e0244b9b9c074dce1&#34;&gt;White Whale Blubber&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;white-whale-bone:14154d75c456ce7e0244b9b9c074dce1&#34;&gt;White Whale Bone&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;building-parts:14154d75c456ce7e0244b9b9c074dce1&#34;&gt;Building Parts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;treated-wood:14154d75c456ce7e0244b9b9c074dce1&#34;&gt;Treated Wood&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wood treated with whale oil.  Necessary for most whaling items.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;trading-items:14154d75c456ce7e0244b9b9c074dce1&#34;&gt;Trading Items&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;mocha-dick-scrimshaw:14154d75c456ce7e0244b9b9c074dce1&#34;&gt;Mocha Dick Scrimshaw&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A highly valued decorative item.  Pirate villagers will trade end game Mocha Dick items in exchange for these precious goods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;slaves:14154d75c456ce7e0244b9b9c074dce1&#34;&gt;Slaves&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pirate villagers will trade certain end game Mocha Dick items in exchange for slave chattel.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mocha Dick Whales</title>
      <link>http://ehabit.github.io/mochadick/post/spec/whales/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2015 16:39:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ehabit.github.io/mochadick/post/spec/whales/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h5 id=&#34;baby-beluga:e717e4dde30ab463caf6360abfdef12c&#34;&gt;Baby Beluga&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A baby whale drops a small amount of Baby Whale Blubber and Baby Whale Bone.  Can be found in deep ocean biomes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;orca-whale:e717e4dde30ab463caf6360abfdef12c&#34;&gt;Orca Whale&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are found in frozen ocean biomes.  Because they are under the ice, the player will want to have an ice breaker upgrade attached to their boat before even considering hunting one of these aggressive whales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;humpback-whale:e717e4dde30ab463caf6360abfdef12c&#34;&gt;Humpback Whale&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;sperm-whale:e717e4dde30ab463caf6360abfdef12c&#34;&gt;Sperm Whale&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;nether-whale:e717e4dde30ab463caf6360abfdef12c&#34;&gt;Nether Whale&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;white-whale:e717e4dde30ab463caf6360abfdef12c&#34;&gt;White Whale&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can only be found in the white whale dimension.  Drops White Whale bones and White Whale blubber.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Journey Begins</title>
      <link>http://ehabit.github.io/mochadick/post/mochadickpic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2015 05:14:50 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ehabit.github.io/mochadick/post/mochadickpic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ehabit.github.io/mochadick/mochadick/mochadickpic/journeybegins.png&#34; alt=&#34;Mocha Dick Pic&#34; /&gt;

An Inuit hunter with his harpoon at the ready as he sails across a foggy ocean in search of a baby beluga.  If he doesn&amp;rsquo;t find one soon, he and his family will starve this winter.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>